Hello everyone and welcome to
English Hot, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and today we
have an elementary level lesson for you.
That's right, today
we are getting a tattoo.
Okay, so a tattoo is a picture that you
get on your body and it lasts forever.
That's right.
So we're going to get a
tattoo, we're going to talk
about this very popular
form of art on your skin.
And so let's start with the dialogue, let's
listen to it and we'll be back in a bit.
I have made up my
mind, I'm getting a tattoo.
Really?
Are you sure?
Yeah, why not?
They're trendy and look great.
I want to get a dragon on my
arm or maybe a tiger on my back.
Yeah, but it's something
that you'll have forever.
They use indelible ink that can
only be removed with laser treatment.
On top of all of that,
I've heard it hurts a lot.
Really?
Of course, they use
this machine with the
needle that pokes your
skin and inserts the ink.
Oh, I didn't know that, I thought they
just painted on your skin or something.
I think you should reconsider and
do some more research about tattoos.
Also find out where
the nearest tattoo parlor
is and make sure that you sterilize
needles and place as hygienic.
Maybe I should just get a tongue piercing.
You.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look
at five key words that
we've picked out for you
on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first phrase that we have here
on language takeaway is indelible ink.
That's right.
When you get a tattoo, they draw
it on your skin with indelible ink.
Okay, well, ink is what you find in a pen.
So when you write you write with ink.
And this is something
that you can also paint with.
But in this case, we're
talking about indelible inks.
That means it's going to
be permanent in your skin.
So something that is indelible
means that you cannot delete or erase.
That's right.
You can't take it away.
Okay, indelible ink or sometimes
people just say permanent ink.
That's right.
Okay.
Obviously, if you get
a tattoo with indelible
ink, it is you if you want to get it
removed, now you can with laser treatment.
Okay.
So laser treatment uses
this very strong light
to take the to burn
the ink out of your skin.
And it is something
that you actually have to
go and do many, many times
to get the tattoo removed.
I've also heard that it's very pain.
Yeah, I've heard that it hurts a
lot more than getting the tattoo.
Right.
So laser removal or laser
treatment is something
that you do when you want
to take a tattoo off your body.
I think they also use
laser treatment to remove.
Maybe you have stains on your skin,
like from the sun or even to remove hair.
I heard.
Yeah, laser hair removal
is something that
many people do to take away some of the
hair on their bodies that they don't like.
Okay.
Obviously, because
tattoos are forever, this
friend is asking this
other person to reconsider
and do some more
research about tattoos.
Well, to consider something
means to think about it.
So to reconsider means
to think about it again.
Right.
So if you're going to
make a big decision,
you should reconsider
what you're going to do.
For example, I really want to
have a hamburger for dinner.
Maybe I should reconsider because
hamburgers aren't very healthy.
Maybe I should decide
on a salad or something.
Very good.
Okay.
So to reconsider.
Now, obviously, when we
have a tattoo done, when
we get a tattoo, they
use this little machine
that has a needle inside
and it vibrates very,
very fast and it kind
of injects the ink.
So the friend tells this
person to make sure
that when they use this machine,
they use sterilized needles.
Okay.
So needles are those very small
little things that go into your skin.
They hurt.
And when you get a shot, the
doctor will use a needle as well.
But a sterilized needle
is a needle that is clean.
So something that is
sterilized means clean.
That's right.
But it's clean for medical use.
That means that maybe someone used
alcohol or even fire to clean something.
Okay.
So as you said, it needs to go
through a process to be sterilized.
Like if you wash your
dishes, they're not sterilized.
No, but if you are getting surgery on your
body, the doctor is going to cut you open.
He will use sterilized tools.
Okay.
Very good.
And moving on to our
last word, very much
related to sterilized
needles, we're talking
about something that
is hygienic to make
sure that everything is hygienic
when you get a tattoo done.
Okay.
Well, something that is hygienic is clean.
So if you have a baby,
you want to make sure
that the room that the
baby is in is very hygienic.
So you clean it very
often, maybe some sterilizer
to clean the different
surfaces and things
like that, because
babies can get sick easily.
That's right.
Okay.
Very good.
So we've taken a look
at five keywords there.
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again.
We can review what
we've just learned and we'll
be back in a little bit
with fluency builder.
I have made up my mind.
I'm getting a tattoo.
Really?
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Why not?
The trendy and look great.
I want to get a dragon on my
arm or maybe a tiger on my back.
Yeah.
But it's something
that you'll have forever.
They use indelible ink that can
only be removed with laser treatment.
On top of all of that,
I've heard it hurts a lot.
Really?
Of course.
They use this machine with the needle
that pokes your skin and inserts the ink.
Oh, I didn't know that.
I thought they just painted
on your skin or something.
I think you should reconsider and
do some more research about tattoos.
Also, find out where
the nearest tattoo parlor
is and make sure that you
sterilize needles and places hygienic.
Maybe I should just get a tongue piercing.
You.
Alright, we're back.
Now let's take a look at some
phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
We only have three
phrases today but the first
one is a phrase you'll hear
very, very often in English.
It's, "I've made up my mind.
" That's right.
The dialogue starts by
saying, "I've made up my mind.
I am getting a tattoo.
" So what does it mean if
you have made up your mind?
Well, it means that you
have decided something.
I have decided to do
something and the present
tense of this phrase is to
make up someone's mind.
I make up my mind, you make up
your mind, he makes up his mind.
Okay, so if you're
choosing something or
making a decision, when
you finally make that
decision, that means that
you have made up your mind.
Maybe we're shopping
Marco and you're thinking,
"Well, do I want this
or do I want that?"
Well, I'll say, "Come on
Marco, make up your mind.
" That's right.
It means just pick one, just decide.
Decide.
Very good.
So a very common phrase to make
up your mind, to make a decision.
And well, as we continue
on with the dialogue,
the friend was saying how the tattoos are
forever and if you want to get it removed,
you need to use laser
treatment and ends this
part by saying on top of all
that, I have heard it hurts a lot.
On top of all that,
this means, and even
more, so basically when
you're trying to give
reasons for something,
maybe reasons for doing
something or reasons
for not doing something,
you give your reasons at the end
you say, "And on top of all that.
" So in addition, or even
more than that, this is the case.
Right.
So maybe we're talking about a car and you
say, "Well, that car is not very reliable.
It uses a lot of fuel.
It's very uncomfortable inside
and on top of that, it's expensive.
" And on top of
all that, it's ugly.
That's right.
So you're kind of listing
things, you're telling
the person why you
think something is good
or bad and then you end it by
giving a final reason and on top of that.
Exactly.
All right.
And our last phrase,
it's actually interesting
because the place where you go and
get a tattoo is called a tattoo parlor.
Okay.
It's a parlor.
So this is interesting
because you might
think that you would say a
tattoo shop, but we don't say this.
So think about a beauty
salon or beauty parlor,
a parlor is a shop where we
get our appearance changed.
And in this case, a
tattoo parlor is a special
shop where you can
get a tattoo or in the
case of this person,
maybe get your ears pierced
or your tongue pierced
or your nose pierced.
So a tattoo parlor is
a place to go for that.
All right.
So a lot of phrases there.
Let's review everything one last time
and we'll be back to talk some more.
I have made up my mind.
I'm getting a tattoo.
Really?
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Why not?
They're trendy and look great.
I want to get a dragon on my
arm or maybe a tiger on my back.
Yeah.
But it's something
that you'll have forever.
They use indelible ink that can
only be removed with laser treatment.
On top of all of that,
I've heard it hurts a lot.
Really?
Of course.
They use this machine with a needle
that pokes your skin and inserts the ink.
Oh, I didn't know that.
I thought they just painted
on your skin or something.
I think you should reconsider and
do some more research about tattoos.
Also, find out where
the nearest tattoo parlor
is and make sure that you
sterilize needles and places hygienic.
Maybe I should just get a tongue piercing.
You.
So, talking about
tattoos and also piercings,
a very popular thing
nowadays, especially
we didn't touch on the piercing aspect of
the dialogue to get your ears pierced or to
get your tongue
pierced means that you're
going to create a hole in your tongue
so you can put a ring or something in it.
That's right.
So, many women have their ears pierced.
This means that they
can wear earrings and
these are small holes in
the bottom of your ear.
But a lot of people
nowadays like to get their
nose pierced so a hole in the side
of the nose or their tongues pierced.
That's right.
You see people now get
eyebrows pierced, their
lips pierced, even
below the lip, I don't
know, near the chin, between the chin and
the lip, they get this thing through it.
It's very interesting.
Yeah, also I've seen belly buttons,
belly buttons like on your ears.
That's right.
And tattoos as well.
Tattoos are so popular
now, people get
tattoos, arms, legs, your
neck, face everywhere now.
That's right.
And there's special
names for these in English.
For example, if you
have a very big tattoo
in your arm from your
shoulder to your elbow,
that's called a sleeve tattoo because
it looks like a permanent sleeve.
That's right.
Actually, women get
tattoos also but for cosmetic
reasons, like many women
get their eyebrows tattooed.
Yeah, I've seen this.
So some women like
to get these tattoos that
look like makeup, so
maybe if you want your
nice eyebrows all the
time, you get these
eyebrow tattoos or if
you want some dark lines
under your eyes like eyeliner,
then you get the eyeliner tattoo.
Also I've seen the lips lip liner
tattoo, they do it around the
lips to make the, it seems like
you consistently have lip liner.
Interesting.
Well, I don't know if I
do that because some
days you just don't
want to wear makeup.
That's right.
But actually tattoos in many
cultures are frowned upon.
I know that until
very recently Japanese
culture, tattoos were
illegal because they were
sitting on the Yakuza
and in Jewish culture,
you're not allowed to
have a tattoo on your body.
And so that if you die with a tattoo,
you cannot go to a Jewish graveyard.
Oh, really?
I've also heard that in
many countries, some
positions, some job positions, you
cannot obtain if you have a tattoo.
Well, it's very interesting.
I don't know why that would influence it.
I think it's definitely
culture to culture
because it's very popular in
America right now to have tattoos.
Right.
But in China and Japan and East
Asia, they're definitely frowned upon it.
Even for example, in
the armed forces in the
United States, it's very popular for them
to have an American flag or something.
You see it all the time in movies.
But in other countries, you cannot
join the armed forces if you have a tattoo.
Interesting.
Well, let us know.
Is having a tattoo okay
in your culture or do
people tend to think
that it's a bad thing?
Or maybe you have a tattoo.
Do you have a tattoo or piercing in
your nose or your lip or your tongue?
Let us know.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see you there.
Bye guys.
Bye.